Your Highness
殿下でんか
The edict is real
聖旨は本当です
It's real
本当だよ
Your Highness
殿下でんか
The edict is real
勅令は本当だよ
Where is Wen Xian?
温賢は
I sent him
私は彼にさせる
To deliver the message
伝えれば
Did he deliver it?
彼は届きましたか
Your Majesty
皇上にお帰り申し上げます
Eunuch Wen
温公
Was beheaded by Prince of Jin
晋の王に斬られた
Beheaded
斬った
Good that he was beheaded
切ってしまえ
Where is my canal?
私の運河はどこですか
Is my canal finished?
私の運河は修理が終わったでしょうか
This
これ
What canal?
どの運河のことですか
Where is my canal?
私の運河はどこですか
Your Majesty
皇帝
Your Majesty, slow down
皇上ゆっくりしてください
The 24th year of Yuankang
元康二十四年
Emperor Sikong Jing
皇帝スコウケイ
Due to taking excessive elixirs
過剰な錬丹を服用したため
And rage affecting his heart
また怒りが心に迫る
Suddenly passed away
急逝
At the same time
そして同時に
Your great army
あなたの大軍
Had already reached the capital
すでに兵は皇城の下まで迫っている
What did you tell me before?
最初あなたたちはどうやってこの王に話したのですか
Saying Qingzhou Army would strike first
慶州軍が先手を打ったと言っているのか
Dongming was impregnable
東明城は鉄壁のように堅固である
Now?
今は
How did it come to this?
今どうしてこんなことになったの
Your Highness
殿下でんか
I'll go out personally
私は自ら城を出る
Command Qingzhou Army to advance
都督が慶州軍を前進させる
As long as I'm there
私がいる限り
Your Highness's trump card remains
殿下の切り札はここにあります
Trump card
切り札
Right
はい
His greatest weakness
彼の最大の弱点
Is still in my hands
まだ私の手の中にある
I'll do as you say
あなたの言う通りに行動します
I'll find a way to get you out
あなたを城の外に出す方法を考えます
Remember
必ず覚えておく
Must not make any mistakes
絶対に失敗してはいけない
Brother
弟
No matter what
どう言おうと
Family is still family
家族は結局家族だ
As your elder brother, I won't take advantage
兄貴分は他人の危険につけこまない
But sending out the Princess Consort
しかし王妃を送り出す
Requires opening the gates
城門を開ける必要があります
This is too dangerous for me
これは私にとってあまりにも危険です
Order your army to retreat thirty li
あなたの部下の大軍に三十里後退するよう命じなさい
I'll send someone to escort the Princess Consort out
私は人を派遣して王妃を城の外に送り出した
But retreating thirty li
しかし三十里後退する
We can just come back
私たちはもうすぐ来ます
Retreat thirty li then return
三十里後退してから戻ってくる
Back and forth
一度きり
Will delay at least two days
少なくとも二日間は遅れる
In that case
こういうふうにして
Qingzhou Army will catch up
慶州の軍が追いついてきた
Brother-in-law
義兄
As long as we act fast enough
私たちが十分に素早く動けば
There's still a chance
全く機会がなかったわけではない
At that time
その時
I'll lead the vanguard
私は先駆けとして来ました